[Music]
all right welcome to another episode of
the wasabi research Club today we are
examining coin join Sudoku weak privacy
guarantees for shared coin mixing
service and we have the author with us
today to talk about it it's not fair to
call this a paper as much as it is a
weakness that was discovered in 2014 and
then published to alert the community
about the concerns with a particular
implementation of coin join we're joined
by Christophe Atlas who will answer
questions and correct anything that I've
said incorrectly about his his work and
he also happens to work for Lockheed
calm which was launching the info which
is the particular protocol in question
that what we are examining here you can
find all of the work and all information
on our github link just below
just a reminder where we are we did four
weeks of coin shuffle plus plush and
cash Fusion last week we talked about
principles in privacy which was much
more philosophical and less math heavy
this week is called Jones todoku and
then of course as always we decide on
the paper for next week at the end of
this call you can find out everything on
our github of course just a reminder
what we talked about last week and when
we talked about prints of privacy
principles we discussed how there are
some common reoccurring things you
shouldn't do when you are trying to
build
privacy tools in anonymity networks and
those things include for example in
secure modes of operations on your
software or optional security that
someone might turn off and never turn
back on or badly labeled off switches
such that the person doesn't know that
they're you know not using a very
critical privacy feature it's important
that the security is convenient because
if it's incredibly inconvenient
everyone will sort of sidestep the
proper way of doing it the full sense of
security is really important to avoid
and ensuring that we have good mental
models for how we think about privacy
for the user such that they know when
they're doing something correctly or
incorrectly and we had an interesting
discussion against options so minimizing
the amount of options that the privacy
software allows for the user we answered
this fundamental question or at least we
try to how should we think about
building or using privacy tools and nm8
networks
we discussed how a tool like tor which
is an anonymity network depends on users
that are entering and exiting the Tor
network and we're not entirely clear who
is who
but there are obviously some problems
with these anonymity networks for
example if there are not enough users in
this case here there's only one user so
it's clear that even though this user is
routing through tor the the output and
input can be linked quite trivially we
talked about how common behavior can
help us link inputs and outputs here we
have a lot of english-speaking people
and then we have a Hungarian speaking
person and we can link the Hungarian
inputs and outputs because there are
minority today we're talking about
something different we're talking about
a flawed implementation at the COI joint
and it's fair to say that this paper it
would have been better had we read this
paper before reading the 2017 knapsack
Khoikhoi paper we're gonna find out that
the knapsack paper in 2017 did a lot
more work and likely built off of this
work so essentially where were we're
examining a paper that has
they cover a lot less ground and I think
that's okay because it was it was very
early on in the Bitcoin privacy timeline
so what is shared coin shared coin is
the coin join implementation by
blockchain info some basic things about
shared coin coin joins that they
typically have more than nine inputs and
more than nine outputs number of inputs
and outputs were often different and
there was a constant minor fee of 0.0001
denomination transactions were also
always broadcast from the blockchain got
info IP address just I've been here for
a brief moment although the number of
inputs and outputs was typically fairly
high since publishing that advisor I did
come across some transactions which were
you know claimed to be shared quite
transactions difficult to verify
decisively but some of them had fairly
low in the ballpark of maybe even four
inputs or outputs so there are some
certainly some exceptions to that rule
for what it's good yeah
and that's a very good thing to point
out I think it's fair to say that apart
from the minor fee and the IP address of
the broadcast there wasn't anything that
clearly outlined these transactions as
being part of shared coin apart from the
fact they have more than the normal
number of inputs and outputs that we
would expect so this is called
fingerprinting so here we're
fingerprinting a shared coin coin shine
and the idea of coins to do sodoku and
again this was it back in 2014 is what
we talked about with the knapsack paper
which is that we want to find groups
subsets of a transaction where input
sums and output sums match and at this
point I think it makes a little bit of
sense to just quickly remind ourselves
what the knapsack paper covered because
in all honesty again the knapsack paper
just did get a more thorough job of
answering this question because again it
was written quite a bit later but the
knapsack paper oh my goodness I think I
might be getting kicked out of the room
pardon me one sec sorry guys I apologize
I'm just gonna be 10 seconds and we're
gonna get back to just be yourself for a
second if you meant yeah a lot of people
are wondering you might have some
insider information why was shared coin
discontinued the founder what I want to
say about that so I think it's fair to
say that as people started exploring
these type of services there was
increasingly concern from a legal
standpoint as to how various governments
about the world might treat such
services and and how this would overall
impact the regulatory attitude towards
Bitcoin people are pretty concerned
about the idea that you know these kind
of services gaining popularity would
paint cryptocurrency the negative light
at the time so I think that is something
that factored into it I think it's also
fair to say that you know compared to
the overall volume in the Bitcoin
network and certainly at blockchain not
info at the time it was a relatively
small poor
of of transactions that were using the
service so probably some combination
that you ultimately led to the decision
not to continue the project I see thank
you I can see that was pretty much
everyone's guest but there was no real
confirmation about that at least as far
as I know so what's up Aviv are you back
oh I'm sorry guys I just had to move
rooms everything is fine we're gonna
continue as as normal so a shared coin
did what the Nats of paper talked about
which was combine transactions together
because there's nothing in the protocol
that excludes one person's inputs and
outputs from not being part of the same
transaction as another individuals
inputs and outputs and you know here we
had an example that we looked at and I
think two months ago where two unique
transactions and on the right you see
them being merged and when we merge two
transactions if we want to investigate
any input and output links what we
really want to do is figure out a
matching sums on the inputs and outputs
so in this case we would take a
hypothetical output like this cup number
50 and then take an input maybe another
input and we try to see the sums on the
left and the right and in this case they
don't match so which I get with a
different set and here you can see that
the inputs and outputs perfectly match
to break this transaction into two
transactions it's like that perfect we
talked about how good is the anonymity
provided by this simple model and can we
improve upon it it turns out that in
2017 it was clear that this naive
approach which is the approach that
shared core took
more and we talked about that at length
during that call we're not going to go
into all of the math stuff but there is
a nice definition that I liked from from
that paper which was we can take any
transaction and break it into sub
transactions at a minimum there's one
sub transaction which is the original
transaction but ideally you want to find
more than that and you want to see how
often inputs and outputs appear in the
same sub transaction and so the the the
paper has this big thing here but all
this this is a fancy equation is saying
is that you simply take all possible
combinations of a transaction and then
and that's on the bottom and on the top
you take only the the combinations where
a particular input and a particular
output were we're together and what you
get at the end is some sort of
percentage of a probability of how
likely they are to be connected now this
was very this is very appropriate and
accurate in terms of being able to break
down a transaction that that has to
believe to be a coin joint so in the
paper
there wasn't an example here of a shared
coin transaction being broken down and
it's it's still a bit hard to see and I
think a few people mentioned this as
well it wasn't entirely clear how this
breakdown was achieved and I think that
in light of the 2017 paper we would not
have agreed this is how we would break
down the transaction so the red here
actually makes a lot of sense because it
is the it's a perfect match but it's
also the case that it's the only inputs
and outputs that have five decimal
places
every other input an output has as fewer
than five decimal places now over here
you know it's this might be a plausible
way to partition this transaction
however it's unclear why we didn't
partition this into five sub
transactions within this transaction for
example you see a 0.03 by BTC over here
and on the right you see a 0.03 so who's
to say that's not one individual that
moved money to themselves and you see
that many many times so it's just
unclear that these entire sets of
transactions must point to each other
and then over here again we have this
problem where there are mappings on the
left side on the right side that were
unclear so you know it comes down to the
fact this was written kind of much much
before a lot of people were interested
in sort of figuring these things out on
that oh you're finishing already okay
and then come back here so I'll just
wrap up and say that you know I looked
at the the github and some of the work
and it does seem like this paper was was
later extended with other people's work
I'm curious about what Christophe has to
say today but I do believe it was
somewhat incomplete but anyways yeah we
can we can open it up to discussion okay
so let's talk about that first so as
soon as I understood it you release this
advisory and shared the cool advisor
into block chaining
and then you did not follow up with code
later on is that correct or I did not
find something yeah that's right so
there was a responsible disclosure
period once blockchain was on board with
kind of publishing it and put something
out there and the graphic is just wrong
obviously I put it together a little
hasty I don't remember exactly what the
mistake was that caused that that error
but some yeah that I never got around to
really correcting it but you know I
figured that the the gist of it was
expressed as far as the code goes I was
never really very happy with the tool
and I did become aware of some other
people working on similar tools the main
one that has really advanced since then
is now I guess the repositories under
the SMR I guys but Boltzmann is a a
transaction analysis tool that can do
this kind of comment or comment or
subset some knapsack problem kind of
analysis and so I just never bothered to
really clean up the code and really get
it out there because I figured that this
other tool was was better so that's the
story as far as the source code goes
thank you I was actually thinking maybe
you actually had some holistic
assumptions that you could make the blue
connections there but but okay so that's
not the case but Aviv even that you you
put a tick there that that the the red
is is good right
but even that's not not correct because
you you might find a soft set there and
you might and you find corresponding
subsets from the remaining inputs and
outputs but that doesn't really matter
because what really matters is that all
the possible subset combinations so if
the red could even be
if you can create subsets with the
output that some of the Red Coins are in
then you would have to do do your
calculations there you know what I mean
absolutely I only put a checkmark saying
that at least this sort of intuitively
makes sense but you're entirely right
the red outputs also could be put into
other subsets
so my point is crystal until you find
all the possible subset combinations you
cannot really make a conclusive
statement of any of the these subsets
you could start the red ones for the red
ones just looking at it briefly it looks
to me like we know that the red ones all
go together they may and then the same
user you know the same key holder let's
say may also own other inputs and
outputs including the possibility that
all of them are owned by the same person
that's not actually how shared quite
service ever worked so that's not really
a possibility but but as far as the
subset-sum issue goes we know the red
ones go together but they could include
other inputs and outputs for that
particular key holder it's not fair to
say I'm not sure about that politically
I think this well if you so so for
example one of the one of the
efficiencies that I try to gain in the
system is it would start at the least
significant digits from the end of the
the decimals right and start matching
from there and kind of work its way up
and so you can see obviously like a
vivre mentions that there's not enough
decimals in the the other categories too
to create decimals that far down in the
number so I won't try to do the math of
my head but I'm pretty sure that that's
kiss
okay okay that's interesting that
actually yeah that's another topic that
I wanted to bring up that let me read
from the paper where is it
for the sake of speed efficiency the
tool currently processes the transaction
by examining one digit at a time in the
inputs and outputs working its way from
the right to left this is faster because
transactions typically involve inputs
and outputs with many zeros which can be
ignored by processing given digit it's
actually it may be even a new hair
ristic or or one of the heuristic that
Eaton Hammond was talking about when we
were talking about knife conjuring so
definitely an interesting that you can
just it was it's not a isn't a matching
heuristic but it's a way of trying to
speed up the process which I resorted to
because the rest of my code was so
horribly inefficient as far as computing
the subset something like that that I
tried to incorporate that and there
about if there is it was a bit buggy and
you know so that's that's what I never
put the code out there didn't feel like
trying to get it all result but it was
working well enough that you know we
could say decisively we could grab a
bunch of shared coin transactions show
that some of these definitely were
matched up and and put it put it out
there that the service was not working
in the way that you would see on the
Left you know someone naive naively
looking the transaction on the left side
of it might say oh it's a lot of them
put them up puts must be love obviously
there but in reality that's not how it
was workings and you did not have any
other so you didn't know how many users
are in the transaction and you did not
know how many inputs or outputs one user
would create so so these assumptions you
you did not have any of that yeah that's
correct so if you if you look at that
shared coin
source-code the server side of the welt
both the server side and the client side
technically were published the the short
coin server code has been inked from
github but I imagine that if you looked
around a little bit you could find it
elsewhere but anyway so you know the way
the server and the code works was kind
of coordinates these joins there's all
these parameters that you can set in you
know a JSON file or something like that
in it so that will define things like
you know the minimum and maximum number
of users you know a min maximum of
amounts and so forth so that there's
been various little parameters there and
those were tweaked over time some of
those tweaks seemed to have been
published to the shared coin github
server but of course we don't know for
sure whether all of the changes that
were implemented on the server resulting
on on change oints we're actually you
know put on on github I don't have any
insider information on that so so the
way that the number of you things like
the number of users and some of the
particulars about how these things are
structured probably changed over time
and we can see some of that suggested in
the commits to the server repo over 10mm
that's a really interesting point that
that blockchain analyst is really having
a hard time of when when some parameters
and changing in some wallets and then
when when do users upgrade for
hypothetically someone could have
downloaded the server code and run their
own sure coin instance right and they
could have taken the client code and
tweaked out or written their own client
so it's even possible that not all of
these shared coin transactions
quote-unquote were run by a blockchain
dot info at the time it's possible with
other people who are doing it I find
that to be somewhat unlikely or if it
did I would expect it to be a very very
low volume of transactions on on chain
but it's hypothetically possible
and you know at the time I think people
who were thinking about running mixers
whether they were custodial or not they
were kind of thinking about this issue
of denied you know plausible deniability
in it you know this idea like well who's
to say that I was the guy who
facilitated this this mixing transaction
right so I think that's one of the
reasons why the source code was kind of
published out there
it's a big guillotine on my part but
seems reasonable to me mm-hmm so most of
my larger question or yeah most of my
larger questions are answered already so
I have some small one but I I leave
others the opportunity but but before
that I just want to know that this seems
like huge amounts of him huge number of
inputs and outputs and I I still can't
believe that you could write a efficient
algorithm to do that because I actually
tried it myself I was actually trying to
figure your shared Cohen Cohen joins to
the COO but but before that when we were
in the nob suck papered I I wrote it on
it was like 6 inputs 6 outputs and and I
mean maybe it was just my code so slow
and yeah well some of these well the
efficiency things I mentioned around
decimal place and so forth
definitely helped speed things up I did
a lot of pre calculation and pre
generating tables that could be quickly
looked up but some to be honest some of
the transactions some of the larger
transactions it would take days on my
laptop to try and process them I was too
cheap to like you know bias and serious
hardware to do it and some of them of
are just completely out of reach
so yeah so so as far as preventing like
mediocre computer scientists from
analyzing these transactions the sheer
number of inputs and outputs worked
pretty well but I wouldn't you know I
wouldn't trust it against someone whose
job it is to you to do this kind of
analysis
you know it is probably not not only
your laptop it's you know it's not even
exponentially it is combinatorics and
combinatorics leaves exponential
functions in in the mud that they are
even faster but it might also be
interesting to talk a little bit about
like what we're seeing in this
transaction so this if I can assume it's
a little fuzzy but you know in this this
image that a veve has up from the
advisory you can see on the left-hand
side for example a bunch of inputs of
point 0 1 BTC right and it's kind of if
you if you ever use shared coin back in
the day when it was running it would you
would have to wait a few minutes for the
whole process to work and and well let's
just take a moment to like remember how
it works
so it was web web wallet only and one of
the more interesting things about it was
that it always did multiple rounds of
joining you never had just one round you
had to have it I think it was at least
two and they did the maximum was 5 or
something like that so the longer that
used you the more rounds and you hit
there's like a little drop-down that
where you could select how many rounds
you're going to do to commit to and the
the longer the more rousey picks the
longer it would take obviously and you
would pay a bit more in you know
transaction fees as well and so one of
my side projects right now i'm trying to
go back to you Chery coin and do some
more fingerprinting analysis but one of
the interesting is to look at the inter
transaction fingerprinting as well
because there's for all shared coin
transactions there was always a clear
beginning middle and end to all of the
these these rounds so if you were a user
back in the day like it used to take a
few minutes
generally speaking for your web all to
kind of wait around and find partners
and so forth
and I can't remember exactly what gave
you this idea but I have a strong
suspicion
again no insider information here but a
strong suspicion that not all of the
funds that are being mixed together came
from users of blockchain not info time I
have a suspicion that the company at the
time may have been including some funds
as well whether that want the company
there are some external source I don't
know but so when we see these these
repeted repetitive amounts of like point
zero one ptc for example this is
suggestive to me based on the other like
you know kind of rumors that were
circulating i think it may have the the
guy then may have put this out there at
some point in the past like hey we're
trying to make this service a little
faster by trying to add some liquidity
or whatever but it certainly looks like
something is being structured here in
that maybe the service is injecting
these inputs along with the user inputs
so the top two in red right they look
like no effort has been done to prepare
them for this round of shared coin and
then some of them are much more rounded
amounts and so I think it's fair to
speculate that maybe some of these
rounded amounts came from from the
company or from the service however want
to put it and so I strongly suspect that
if someone really sat down and looked at
this carefully they could really really
pull these transactions apart because
they would be able to isolate inputs
coming from the server service versus
the users and there might only be one to
three users in this join outside of
funds that are coming from you know
let's say a custodial hot wallet that
was contributing liquidity if I had gone
further with this you know research I
think that's what I would have started
to find is that we could really pull
apart the users from the service funds
and
then we would find not that many users
per joint I it's interesting I never
occurred to me I actually used share
coin quite a lot like I don't know ten
times something like that but yeah it it
was almost felt somewhat instant and I
don't know you can you can say that
broke Cheney who had that volume but
yeah if you looked at the blockchain and
and you found that that it's it's there
that is a big big veil there although I
mean even if injecting volume here is
not that much of an issue from privacy
vise because the this you are under the
assumption that the server knows the
links anyway so it's like if the server
participates in the joins then more
power to you you know it would only be a
problem if you could see your finger and
characterize the files coming from the
server and separate that those are from
the users you know in if the server was
not adding its funds that such a way
that actually made the subset-sum
problem harder then you know then it
might just be completely useless for for
the server to its own funds and it you
know it would have the kind of privacy
effect that is the worst case scenario
where you convince the users that they
have all this privacy but it does
nothing to actually deter the attackers
in the future you know and since the
blockchain is an indelible piece of
forensic evidence that just gets easier
to analyze it for time that's kind of a
it's kind of a big deal in my opinion
all right so guys what do you have let
me organize my notes start talking first
of you're part of the Bitcoin privacy
initiative as well as block
tell me about what you do in both of
those roles just a bit more yeah sure so
the the two are completely separate the
Bitcoin open privacy project was
something that we started back in maybe
2014-2015 and it really it's me and you
know I had full of other folks who I was
in touch with and we were interesting in
you know promoting Bitcoin privacy and
coming up with some standards you know
so one of the products that we have for
example we call like the top threats to
Bitcoin privacy and it's modeled after
the the a wasp top ten for for web
applications and you know it's this very
famous application security reference
guide that gets updated here and there
so that's that was sort of the idea that
we had for the organization was a kind
of open source
you know nonprofit kind of organization
to to to look at privacy and to try and
promote it through streaming where
necessary and the shaming element came
in the form of occasionally putting out
some reports where we tried to come up
with something semi objective criteria
for privacy in different wallets and
really try to highlight some of the the
deficits that were that were out there
to make it clear to people you know what
they're giving up and help them make a
little bit better decisions as far as
consumers kind of go you know entirely
separate from that I have also been
working as a security engineer for
blocked and calm I joined somewhere in
late 2014 so it was a bit after this
research was when it was after I had
been working on this research and
published the Advisory so and you know
they did I didn't necessarily come on
board specifically because of this
advisory but if I was doing various
things in Bitcoin and privacy and
security and so that's when I started
working there as a security engineer
okay that's awesome so how do you feel
that blockchain wallet is he's aligned
to your privacy principles that you hold
how does that just Square dad great
question
so when the open Bitcoin privacy project
looked at wallets in the past the
overall the blockchain wallets and this
it's been a few years since we've really
updated that mostly cuz there haven't
been really exciting improvements to to
to observe in Bitcoin privacy but um
back when we first our last report
blockchain wallet didn't really stand
out in the pack among competitors I
think that as a company the privacy of
users you know it's it's important to
them but you know again from a
potentially legal perspective and just
looking at the the demand from users
there's not that many users who are
really really excited passionate about
privacy focused software in Bitcoin yet
I hope that's something that will change
in the future but I don't think there's
a huge market for that yet and so the I
think the lack of demand and some of the
other concerns around these technologies
have made it such that you know
blockchain comm has not been trying to
push the forefront of the stuff
necessarily as it did previously you
know I think shared coin was an earnest
attempt to really they were they were
one of the first coin join pieces of
software out there came out pretty soon
like this is clearly something that Ben
was passionate about and started working
on very soon after coin jam was
announced as an idea and I think that
just the demand and and stuff hasn't
really made it a priority for the
company overall so
I wouldn't I wouldn't say that my
relationship with the company is
primarily motivated by you know privacy
related stuff just just a quick note
here that from the paper in a sample of
20,000 consecutive transactions across
45 Brooks in the blockchain 2.6 percent
of the transactions fit the profile of
shared coin transactions this small
sample constitutes only of seven hours
of Bitcoin transactions from March 27
2014 2.6 percent and I think you
identified these transactions like
almost probably almost hundred percent
certainty like it comes from work chain
info that's for sure and it has a bunch
of inputs and bunch of outputs which is
very rare that that kind of thing is
happening or or like never yeah there
may have been some false positives with
like mining pools and mining pool
payouts and gambling transaction payouts
and stuff like that that you know either
we're using blockchain comm info time
API to kinda broadcast the transactions
or you know sometimes it was just
happenstance that it happened to kind of
get early on broadcasted through
blockchain and characterized that way so
there's there's some false positives
than there very likely but just to give
a rough estimate say probably easily
it'll be tonight percent of those
transactions that would be an accurate
characterization now you might be
tempted to say well a 2.6 percent of
transactions that seems like a lot of
volume but keep in mind that the volume
at that time was a good deal lower than
what we've experienced since then on the
Bitcoin blockchain
so you know all that might seem like a
lot of users it's it's actually not a
huge bail
hmm yeah make make sense although it is
a huge amount because whenever I said
whenever you sent a shared coin
transaction there was a bunch of people
to join with you in that half an hour
and I'm I don't know if we could even do
that with wasabi I'm I think we couldn't
so that's that's a that's a it's a very
decent amount so to say also one more
note that shared coin had a very
compared to shared Kohinoor the privacy
tycoon later coming on to bitcoin is
kind of like ux step back in a sense
that's a yeah sure coin may have been it
may still have be out of all the
possible clients i've implemented coin
joint technology it may have been the
most popular by number of users or
volume which is sad to say because it's
quite ancient now but that's that's
really possible anyway what do you guys
have well do you guys I can ask
questions indefinitely if anyone else
wants to ask please cut me off okay
Christophe one thing that's a bit
confusing is the sort of lack of
consensus about the legal status of
something like a coin join at wasabi
were pretty convinced and we have a good
legal team that thinks about this we're
pretty convinced that coin joint isn't
Oh
violating any laws and that it couldn't
be considered to violate any laws I'm
just curious as to why you think there
is this disc Lera T you know it's a
completely non custodial thing which
means you're talking about privacy
software interacting with other privacy
software doing what the protocol allows
it to do you know arguably the Lightning
Network is is more custodial and has
similar privacy features and
participants helping others achieve that
privacy so what why why are we seeing
all this confusion I'm certainly no
lawyer but I have talked to lawyers very
active in this space and I think it's a
little naive and I've made this what L
characterized as a mistake before is
that it's a little naive to think about
in terms of like well what in this
particular snapshot in time is legal
versus not legal you know there's a lot
of different jurisdictions out there
laws can change over time and I think
people who are high up in the the
Bitcoin ecosystem who are doing things
like interacting interfacing directly
with regulators at you know major
conferences and stuff like that they
don't just think about you know what's
what's gonna show the legal opinion
right now but what's the general
attitude towards regulators towards the
the industry as a whole and that that
fall is almost more under the heading of
politics and I think this is this is
something that maybe people don't have a
lot of insight into because it doesn't
get discussed publicly is there people
out there who are who are lawyers but
they are having conversations with
regulators and horse-trading
you know as far as what kinds of
features can can be gotten away with and
what's what's going to darken the
attitude of regulators towards
cryptocurrency
if you think about the natural
geopolitical tensions between
cryptocurrency and regulators politician
governments as a whole it's kind of
miraculous that there hasn't been more
of a crackdown than there already has
right and I think part of the
explanation for that is that people in
these kinds of backroom situations have
been conservative and careful about
making decisions in that space so if
there's some cup if there's some big
company I don't I don't want to pick on
blockchain in particular but take any
large company in the space that has you
know a lot of users has a lot of volume
on blockchains
has a lot of assets under management and
you know a lot of funding and a lot to
lose by being shut down on right that
that is very different you you that's a
very different place to be in than say
you know a relatively small project and
I think a lot of the being a kind of
privacy Bitcoin privacy wallets out
there would polyfill amount more under
that heading than the mega companies
that are out there and it's just it's a
different experience does that answer
your question Esther yeah that's a very
good response I definitely didn't think
about it in that light because it would
seem incredibly hard to believe that
some company is forced to shut down
because of coin join but I I appreciate
that they might be shut down for other
reasons where coin joint played a role
in the decision and the and swayed
people to that so um yeah the the
shutdown thing is like yeah obviously
that's the worst that's the worst case
the worst case scenario is like all of
your executives get arrested inside to
celebrate theythey can shut down and
underseas and stuff like that there's so
many negative things that can happen and
there's so much backroom stuff that can
happen you know the interface between
companies and regulators that
you know and I think it's it's not that
helpful to think it in that cut that
kind of binary way like do I want to put
this feature out there or will I get you
down right and it's it's it's me a lot
more nuanced by that I think there's a
lot of people who you know they see
these regulators as these kind of like
sharks swimming through the ocean and
they say oh well you know he hasn't
eaten this guy in that guy and he hasn't
eaten me I look good all the risks that
I'm taking mean this truck hasn't me
it's like Jackies you're you're a little
sardine right he's the you're not either
that guy snack for him so it's it's it's
surprisingly complicated and I was not
privy to a lot of that sort before kind
of getting more involved in the industry
[Music]
all right I think my last question is
insignificant so I'm not going to ask so
questions three two one what do you guys
have do you have something or should we
should we wrap it up I have no questions
it's pretty clear to me okay anyway I'm
going to ask my last question so in the
paper you talked about Bitcoin s X as
one of the first clients to implement Co
enjoin do you remember that yeah what
what was that what was the story behind
it you know if I recall correctly
Bitcoin
s X was like um it was a pretty simple
simple little GUI client that did this
kind of coin joint stuff that was very
naive it was very restrictive about what
kind of transactions what kind of inputs
could be involved that were allowed
probably had like an IRC back-end or
something like that
was severely something that some so much
tape together
I also remember that shortly after it
was announced there were like a aware
fakes going around right it and so forth
so people really you know pissed
about having coins stolen from you no
malicious copies of it back in the Wild
West of Bitcoin yeah I don't I don't
recall whether SX ended up being part of
some what somehow related to dark wallet
if any of those guys were involved in SX
I seem to recall there may have been
some relationship there but I can't I
can't see that for sure thank you and
that concludes our episode for today
Thank You Krista I really appreciate
that you come and it was it was I think
this is the first time we talked it was
nice nice view here yeah thank you so
much for having us
it's a pleasure to talk to you guys I'm
excited to you I haven't had a chance to
check out your past episodes yep and I'm
gonna go through the the archive and
looks like it's a really good study
group and just so you know um as far as
shared coin goes I'm still working a
little bit in this area again one of my
side projects that I'm gonna finish
eventually is doing a more thorough job
of fingerprinting these transactions
trying to quantify them and I'd like to
see how some of these were modern
analysis tools like Boltzmann fair
against some of these transactions and
what we can kind of what we can find out
from there it's a it's a very good that
you brought up Watchmen because so I
even asked everyone should boatsman me
the next one or do you want again a
voting for for the next is boys month
fine with everyone yeah
Boltzmann is fine but we're not able to
get the authors on correct I don't know
we are going to ask so we'll see
okay alright so increased oh yeah if you
want to come next week then it's going
to be both one it's a
it's more fun to to look through the
paper when there is a talk on the end of
the week HUS hit them then alone alright
alright cool
thank you guys Christophe view you want
to maybe ask something or or or do you
do you feel there is something you did
not have the chance to say I think I
said everything if you guys have any
feedback about my participation in the
in the chat giving a giving you an
overview of the research I found happy
to hear any feedback that you have about
that or things that you'd like to see me
research more in the future anything in
that area alright then thank you guys
like subscribe and for that three people
who got to the end of this video
congratulations now you know more about
Cohen joins to Dooku then you know
before so thank you and have a good day
and good night everyone
bye-bye take a bow thanks crystal
you